Now, we have a painting we want to show.
It's thought to be from the 11th century,
and it's showing you some rather interesting stuff.
And it has some bearing, I think, on what's
going on in the economy and society and the new policies.
But let's take a look at it and I'll point some things out for you
and you can, perhaps, do some more with it on your own.
Let's begin on the right side of the painting.
You see the building in the lower right, and that wooden structure,
pointless wooden structure that appears right before the front door.
Well, those structures were typical in cities in the 11th century.
They disappear later, but in the 11th century they're still typical.
They're put in front of wine houses, restaurants, and hotels.
And if you look to the right there and look around, what you're seeing,
I think, is a hotel, an inn.
And right out of the front door you see an innkeeper peeking.
He's peeking out of the front door.
Well, why is there an inn there and what are they doing?
Let's go to the center of this picture for a moment.
There is-- you see a house, two floors, a fancy house, open.
And in the middle of it, what do you see?
Down at the bottom that's a water wheel.
It's a horizontal water wheel and you can see the water gushing in,
and it turns that wheel and above, on the second floor,
you see the stones grinding wheat-- I assume it's wheat-- into flour.
Now, if you look at the rest of painting,
you'll see that in one way or another everything revolves around that.
So people are going to the inn because they're bringing grain to the mill.
Perhaps, selling it, perhaps, paying the mill to work on it.
You see different kinds of boats.
You see people doing different parts of the job of getting grain milled.
And then over in the left, up in a pavilion in the upper left,
you see a group of people sitting around a table.
And as far as we know, those are officials.
So this mill is not a private mill.
It's a government mill.
Given the looks of things, it's a mill in the city or on the edge of the city.
The officials are there running it.
And so at the very least, this is a picture
that shows the role of government in the economy.